

# Raffaele Vergnani

Transport and environmental policy expert

My background is geography and spatial planning. Gained 8 years of professional experience as officer and analyst in environmental and transport policy sectors, in front-row research, consultancy and tech companies. Worked on 8 projects financed by EU bodies and delivered 10+ targeted studies to the EU Commission, the EU Parliament and the Alpine Convention. Truly enthusiast about sustainable mobility, digital innovations and excited about the radical changes that the whole sector is facing.

vergnanir@gmail.com

+39 348 8892092

Berlin, Germany

in linkedin.com/in/raffaelevergnani

#### **SOFT AND HARD SKILLS**

Critical thinking

Communication

Public speaking

Teamwork

Versatiliity

Initiative

EU Project Managemen

Microsoft Office 365

Tableau / Power BI

Pytho

ArcGIS

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Network Planning Manager - Italy

Flixmobility GmbH

03/2020 - 12/2020

Market leader operating international long distance bus and train services.

#### Accomplishments

- Conducted strategic planning of new long distance bus lines across Italy and beyond.
- Prepared ramp-up / ramp-down scenarios to selected bus lines, as a response to COVID-19 pandemic.
- Performed competitors and policy analysis in the long-distance road transport sector.

# **Transport Policy Analyst**

TRT Trasporti e Territorio Srl

09/2016 - 02/2020

Consultancy specialised in economics, mobility planning and transport modelling.

#### Accomplishments

- Delivered 3 research studies on transport policy issues for the EU Commission and the EU Parliament.
- Completed 6 EU-funded projects focusing on passenger transport and logistics.
- Published +30 articles / case studies on web portals with EU-wide coverage on urban mobility.
- Elaborated concept & project ideas into concrete proposals to be eligible to EU financing.

# **Project Officer**

#### European Academy of Bolzano (EURAC)

07/2012 - 08/2016

Private research centre, focused on environmental, energy and policy issues.

#### Accomplishments

- Co-authored 8 research studies in the field of urban mobility and environmental protection.
- Completed 2 EU-funded projects on transport and tourism in the Alps.
- Scientific advisor for the project "AlpInfoNet" (Alpine Space Programe 2007-2013).
- Appointed as external consultant of the Italian Ministry of the Environment, within the framework of the Alpine Convention.
- Member of the Italian delegation of the Working Groups "Transport" and "UNESCO World Heritage" of the Alpine Convention.

Berlin, Germany

Milan, Italy

Rome, Italy

## **EDUCATION**

## Data Analytics bootcamp Ironhack

01/2021 - 03/2021

Executive Master in "Environment, Innovation and Management"

**LUISS Business School** 

11/2015 - 01/2017 Rome, Italy

M.Sc. Geography and Spatial Planning

University of Bologna

03/2009 - 03/2011 Bologna, Italy

**Visiting Erasmus student** 

University College Cork

09/2007 - 05/2008 Cork, Rep. of Ireland

**B.Sc. Geographical Sciences** 

University of Bologna

09/2005 - 03/2009 Bologna, Italy

#### **LANGUAGES**

Italian French English German

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency Limited Working Proficiency

#### **AWARDS**

Commendations received for the work administered during the Italian Presidency of the Apine Convention (01/2013 - 12/2014)

Italian Ministry of the Environment, Secretariat of the Alpine Convention.

- Commendations obtained by the Italian Under-Secretary of State of the Italian Ministry of the Environment Ms. Barbara Degani.
- Commendations given by the Secretary General of the Alpine Convention, Mr. Markus Reiterer.

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

#### Tourist guide

Municipality of San Martino in Rio (RE)

02/2009 - 07/2014

Tasks

 Performed guided tours in Italian & English for visitors accessing the medieval castle located in S. Martino in Rio (Italy) and the annexed museum of agriculture. Occasional collaboration.

#### **INTERESTS**

Tennis Cycling Travelling Hiking Micromobility E-mobility Geopolitics Finance and Investments

Berlin, Germany